Ratish Udawat

 ♥ Bengaluru, India
 ■ ratishudawat@gmail.com
 □ (+91) 823-322-3898
 in/ratishudawat
 ♥ github.com/ratishudawat

SUMMARY

Senior Software Engineer with 7+ years of experience building and maintaining complex web applications. Proven ability to architect, design, and implement solutions across the entire development lifecycle. Skilled team player with a passion for innovation and delivering exceptional user experiences.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Unify Technologies

July 2022 - Present, Bengaluru, IN

- · Client Harman International.
- · Designed and implemented high-performance tables using AG Grid and Tanstack, capable of managing up to 1 million logs efficiently.
- · Integrated a DLT parser and real-time hardware logging into Harman's automotive tool.
- · Successfully handling a high frequency of unified logs, and enhancing system performance by 30%.
- \cdot Recognized as the "Star Performer for Q1-2023" for exceptional contributions.
- · React, Node, Typescript, Qt, Electron, Eclipse Theia, Tailwind.

Engineer - Product and Platform

Altimetrik

October 2020 - September 2021, Bengaluru, IN

- · Client PayPal.
- · Worked on Paypal Activities component to successfully achieve 50% ramp on tech stack migration.
- · Successfully driven the GoPay-Paypal integration for China data centres.
- · React, Node, Dust.js, Java, Docker, Kubernetes.

Software Engineer

HolidayIQ (Acquired by LastMinute.com in Feb'23)

August 2018 - August 2020, Bengaluru, IN

- · Worked on building a custom framework to create dynamic chat forms using React, which increased the daily leads count by 20%.
- · Created a tracking engine from scratch using Express and handlebars to generate custom reports on user engagement.
- · Node.js, React, Laravel, MySQL, Docker, Kafka, Elasticsearch.

Full Stack Developer

Vaahika

March 2017 - April 2018, Jaipur, IN

- · Built a comprehensive admin dashboard and client-facing website from the ground up, ensuring seamless integration and a positive user experience.
- · Developed and integrated robust RESTful APIs for an Android app, significantly improving data retrieval speed and user interaction.
- · Sails.js, Handlebars, React, Express, Material UI, MySQL.

SKILLS

BACK END DEVELOPMENT | Node.js ⋅ Express.js ⋅ Python ⋅ Java

 $\textbf{FRONT} \ \textbf{END} \ \textbf{DEVELOPMENT} \ | \ \textbf{React} \cdot \textbf{Redux} \cdot \textbf{JavaScript} \cdot \textbf{Bootstrap} \cdot \textbf{Materialize} \cdot \textbf{Tailwind} \cdot \textbf{HTML} \cdot \textbf{CSS}$

 $\label{eq:miscellaneous} \textbf{Miscellaneous} \mid \textbf{SQL} \cdot \textbf{PostgreSQL} \cdot \textbf{MySQL} \cdot \textbf{AWS} \cdot \textbf{EC2} \cdot \textbf{DynamoDB} \cdot \textbf{S3} \cdot \textbf{Lambda} \cdot \textbf{Elasticsearch} \cdot \textbf{Eclipse Theia} \cdot \textbf{Kubernetes} \cdot \textbf{Docker} \cdot \textbf{Kafka} \\ \textbf{SOFT SKILLS} \mid \textbf{Team player} \cdot \textbf{Bias for action} \cdot \textbf{Deliver results} \\ \textbf{MySQL} \cdot \textbf{AWS} \cdot \textbf{EC2} \cdot \textbf{DynamoDB} \cdot \textbf{S3} \cdot \textbf{Lambda} \cdot \textbf{Elasticsearch} \cdot \textbf{Eclipse Theia} \cdot \textbf{Kubernetes} \cdot \textbf{Docker} \cdot \textbf{Kafka} \\ \textbf{SOFT SKILLS} \mid \textbf{Team player} \cdot \textbf{Bias for action} \cdot \textbf{Deliver results} \\ \textbf{MySQL} \cdot \textbf{AWS} \cdot \textbf{EC2} \cdot \textbf{DynamoDB} \cdot \textbf{S3} \cdot \textbf{Lambda} \cdot \textbf{Elasticsearch} \cdot \textbf{Eclipse Theia} \cdot \textbf{Kubernetes} \cdot \textbf{Docker} \cdot \textbf{Kafka} \\ \textbf{SOFT SKILLS} \mid \textbf{Team player} \cdot \textbf{Bias for action} \cdot \textbf{Deliver results} \\ \textbf{MySQL} \cdot \textbf{AWS} \cdot \textbf{EC2} \cdot \textbf{DynamoDB} \cdot \textbf{S3} \cdot \textbf{Lambda} \cdot \textbf{Elasticsearch} \cdot \textbf{Eclipse Theia} \cdot \textbf{Eclipse$

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Engineering

Rajasthan Technical University \cdot Jaipur, IN \cdot June 2017

• Relevant Coursework: Object Oriented Programming, Databases, Data Structures and Algorithms, Operating Systems, Computer Networks, Machine Learning, Data Mining, Advance Data Structures and Algorithms, Information Retrieval, Image Processing

CERTIFICATIONS

Redhat Openstack (6.0 Mitaka)

Linux World Informatics Pvt Ltd · 2015

Redhat Certified Engineer (RHCE v7)

Linux World Informatics Pvt Ltd · 2016

HOBBIES

Football, Travel, Fitness, Nutrition